By my third Command Spell, I order you again.
第三の令呪を以て 重ねて命ずる
No!
やめろおおお
Saber, destroy the Grail.
セイバー 聖杯を破壊しろ
How could I have understood him if three
commands were all that existed between us?
たった三度の命令のみの関係で いったい何が見抜けたというのか
私はもっと身近に仕えてくれた者たちの心すら見通せなかったというのに
I couldn't even comprehend the hearts
of those who had served right beside me.
Perhaps this is all a punishment for a king who couldn't understand others...
これは全て
人の気持ちが分からない王に課せられた罰だったのかもしれない
Th-That's...
あれは
Ridiculous...
馬鹿な
That's ridiculous!
そんな馬鹿な
切嗣
Kiritsugu...
What's wrong, Ilyasviel?
どうしたの イリヤスフィール
Um, I had a really scary dream.
あのね 怖い夢を見たの
I dreamed that I became a cup...
イリヤが杯になっちゃう夢
...and seven really big lumps appeared inside me...
イリヤの中にね ものすごく大きな塊が七つも入ってくるの
It felt like they'd tear me apart.
イリヤは破裂しそうになって
It was really scary, but I couldn't run away...
とっても怖くて
でも 逃げられなくて
そのうち ユスティーツァさまの声が聞こえてね
Then I heard Justica-sama's voice.
A big black hole opened up over my head.
頭の上に真っ黒い大きな穴が開いて
And then, the world burned.
それで 世界が燃えちゃうの
切嗣がそれを眺めて泣いているの
Kiritsugu saw it happen and cried.
Mommy, is Kiritsugu okay?
お母様 切嗣は平気かな
Is he alone and really scared?
一人ぼっちで 怖い思いをしてないかな
It's okay.
大丈夫 あの人はイリヤのために頑張るわ
He's doing his best for you.
私たちの祈りを きっと彼は遂げてくれる
He'll make sure our prayers are realized,
もう二度と イリヤが怖い思いをしないで済むように
so you'll never have to be scared again.
うん そうだね
Yeah, you're right.
You must be right.
そうだよね
切嗣は頑張り屋さんだもの
Kiritsugu always works hard.
I'm sure he'll come home soon after finishing his important work.
大切なお仕事をきちんと終わらせて
もうすぐ帰ってくるよね
Hey, Sakura-chan...
よう 桜ちゃん
Uncle?
おじさん
I've come to save you.
助けに来たよ もう大丈夫だ
Everything's okay now.
Let's go.
行こう
Sakura!
桜
Sakura! Sakura!
桜 桜 桜
Sakura!
Kariya-kun.
雁夜君
葵さん
Aoi-san.
Thank you, Uncle Kariya.
ありがとう 雁夜おじさん
Thank you.
ありがとう
雁夜お父さん
Daddy Kariya!
馬鹿な人
He's so stupid.
お爺さまに逆らうから
That's what happens when you disobey Grandpa.
ここは
Where am I?
You're a difficult man to look after.
世話の焼ける男だ
瓦礫の下からお前を掘り当てるのは難儀であったぞ
Digging you from the rubble was quite troublesome.
Gilgamesh, what happened?
ギルガメッシュ 何があった
Who can say?
さあな
あの泥がオレを吐き戻したのだ
The mud spat me back out.
どうやら 再びこの時代に君臨し 地上を治めよという天意らしい
It seems to be the will of the gods that I return to this age to rule the world.
受肉を果たしたというのか
So you've achieved true incarnation?
Infuriatingly enough.
業腹だがな
I can't believe we fought over that thing and thought it would grant wishes.
あのような物を願望機などと期待して奪い合っていたとは
此度の茶番 つくづく最後まで度し難い顛末であったな
This play remained a farce to the very end.
I was shot...
私は撃たれた
I have no heartbeat...
鼓動が ない
私に何か治療を施したのか ギルガメッシュ
Did you somehow heal me, Gilgamesh?
Who can say?
さて どうだかな
見たところ死んでいる様子だが
You did look like you were dead.
お前はオレと契約で繋がっていた
You and I are connected by the contract.
オレがあの泥で受肉した拍子に
The moment I gained true incarnation within that mud,
perhaps you too were trapped in some sort of absurdity.
お前はお前で 何らかの不条理に囚われたのかもしれん
You're saying it gave me life?
あれから命を授かったというのか
全てのサーヴァントが消滅し
All the other Servants are gone, which means we have won the Grail.
聖杯を勝ち取ったのは我々だ
綺礼よ
Kirei, behold the results.
その結末を刮目して見るがいい
If the Grail really does grant the victor's wish...
聖杯が真に勝者の願望を汲み取るのであるならば
Kotomine Kirei, this view is what you most desired.
言峰綺礼
この景色こそがお前の求め欲していた物だ
What?
何だ 何なんだ 私は
What am I?
What evil.
なんという邪悪 なんという鬼畜
What cruelty.
This is my wish?
これが私の望み
This destruction and tragedy?
こんな破滅が 嘆きが
This is my pleasure?
私の愉悦だと
こんな歪みが 汚物が
Could Kotomine Risei's seed really have
birthed something so twisted and corrupt?
よりにもよって言峰璃正の種から産まれたと
有り得ん 有り得んだろう
Impossible.
It's impossible!
What's this?
何だそれは
Could my father really have sired a dog?
我が父は狗でも孕ませたというのか
Are you satisfied, Kirei?
満たされたか 綺礼よ
No, not yet.
いいや まだだな
これでは足りん
This isn't enough.
Yes, it's true that I've finally found
the answer in my life of questioning.
確かに 問い続けるだけだった人生に
私はようやく回答を得た
But the problem solving itself was bypassed, and the solution was simply given to me.
ところがな 問題が解かれる過程を省略して
ただいきなり回答を投げ渡され
Just what can I accept about any of this?
これで一体 何をどう納得しろというのだ
The formula that yielded this strange answer
should exist somewhere as a principle with clarity.
こんな怪異な回答を導き出した方程式が
どこかに必ず 明快な理としてあるはずだ
いや あらねばならない
No...
It has to.
問わねばならん 探さねばならん
I must question.
I must search.
I must use the rest of my life to understand it.
この命を費やし
私はそれを 理解しなければ
You never cease to amuse me.
どこまでも飽きさせぬ奴
それでいい
Very well.
神すら問い殺す貴様の求道
Your questions would slay the gods themselves.
I, Gilgamesh, shall watch you in your quest for truth.
このギルガメッシュが見届けてやる
Angra Mainyu...
アンリ ·マユ「Angra Mainyu」
I will reach it again and see it to the end next time.
いつかまた至り そして次こそは見届けよう
Its birth.
あれの誕生を
Its proof of existence.
その存在証明を
Emiya... Kiritsugu?
衛宮 切嗣
I accept your challenge.
受けて立つとも
What's the matter, Kirei?
どうしたのだ 綺礼
Nothing.
いや
I remember that face.
その顔を覚えている
He had tears in his eyes from finding someone still alive.
目に涙を溜めて
生きている人間を見つけ出せたと
心の底から喜んでいる
A man who was happy from the bottom of his heart.
男の姿
He looked so happy that it seemed like
it was him, not me, who had been saved.
それがあまりにも嬉しそうだったから
まるで 救われたのは俺ではなく 男の方ではないかと思ったほど
活きてる
You're alive...
活きてる 活きてる
You're alive! You're alive!
And then...
そうして
死の直前にいる自分が羨ましく思えるほど
Even though I was on the brink of death,
the man was so grateful that it made me jealous.
男は何かに感謝するように
"Thank you", he said.
「ありがとう」と言った
He said he was glad to have found someone,
見つけられて良かったと
and that by saving even one person,
一人でも助けられて
he had saved himself.
救われたと
Episode 25
では 次のニュースです
And now, our next news item.
Fuyuki City
Large Fire in the Fuyuki City New Town
News
At the Fuyuki City New Town...
冬木市新都で昨夜
Did Alexei-san make it back to England safely?
アレクセイさんは 無事にイギリスに着いたかしらねえ
明け方にヒースローから電話してきたよ
He called me this morning from Heathrow.
時差を考えろってんだよ まったく
I told the fool to think about the time difference.
Oh, he called?
あら電話が 気付かなかったわ
I didn't notice.
でも あの人らしいじゃないの
But it's just like him to do that.
Hey, Grandpa and Grandma.
ね お爺さん お婆さん
相談があるんだけど いいかな
There's something I'd like to talk to you about.
What is it?
どうしたんだ 改まって
うん 実はね
Well...
I'm thinking of taking a break from school.
暫く休学しようと思うんだ
Of course, I'll talk to Dad in Toronto about it first.
勿論トロントの父さんにも相談してからだけど
I want to spend my time on something other than my studies at school.
学校の勉強よりも　別のことに時間を使いたくなって
Oh?
ほう
My goodness!
あらまあ
But what brought this on?
でもまたどうして急に
もしかして学校が嫌になったの
You aren't fed up with school, are you?
No, it's not that.
いや　そういう訳じゃないよ
ただね　今まで勉強以外のこと
It's just that I haven't been interested in
anything besides studying in my life so far.
ろくに興味持たなかったのをちょっと後悔してるんだ
I'm regretting that a little.
And so...
それでね　うん
I was thinking of doing some traveling.
旅をしようかと思うんだ
Oh, my!
まあ まあ
聞きましたか グレン
Did you hear that, Glen?
Waver-chan just said something that Alexei-san would have.
ウェイバーちゃんったら急に まるでアレクセイさんみたいなことを言い出したわ
Anyway, I'll have a lot of preparations to do, and I'll need some money.
ともかく まあ 色々準備というか
先立つものも必要になるし
So I figured I'd start by finding myself a part-time job.
まずはアルバイトでも始めようかって
And so...
それで さ
This is the real issue.
ここからが本題なんだけど
If you wouldn't mind...
もし構わないようならさ
Could I stay here until I get things worked out?
目処がつくまでこの家で厄介になっても いいかな
Of course you can!
もちろんですとも
It will be so wonderful to continue to have you here.
ウェイバーちゃんとまだ一緒にいられるなんて 何て素敵なんでしょ
Yes, we'll have to celebrate today!
そうだ 今日はお祝いね
Geez...
まったく
Air Force Technology Research Center
Zero
Fighter
Planes
He's just a spirit, so how is he able to leave such a mess behind?
ただの霊魂ふぜいが
一体どうすりゃこれだけの痕跡を残して行くってんだよ
Really, I wanted him to take me along...
本当は連れて行って欲しかったけどな
I guess that means I'm not quite there yet.
要するに まだ全然なっていないってことだな 僕は
So he never ended up opening this...
結局封も切ってないじゃんか あいつ
Man.
Air Force Technology Research Center
Zero
Fighter
Planes
A pre-order original bonus T-shirt.
初回購入特典 オリジナルTシャツ付き
Who would want something like this?
こんなの欲しがる奴なんているのかよ
Honestly...
まったく
I know that my redeemer lives.
I know that my Redeemer lives
And that, in the end, he will stand upon the Earth.
and that in the end he will stand upon the earth
And after my skin has been destroyed, yet in my flesh,
And after my skin has been destroyed yet in my flesh
I will see God.
I will see God
I, myself, will see him, with my own eyes.
I myself will see him with my own eyes
I, and not another.
I and not another
How my heart yearns within me.
How my heart yearns within me
Amen
Amen.
Rin.
凛
That was an excellent debut as the new family head.
新たな当主の初舞台として まずは充分な働きだ
Your father would've been proud.
お父様もさぞや鼻が高いことだろう
Well done.
ご苦労だった
I'm sure you aren't fully accustomed to your Crest yet.
まだ刻印は完全には馴染んでいないのだろう
Does it hurt?
痛むかね
This is nothing. I'm fine.
こんなの　平気よ
Tokiomi's preparations truly were flawless.
時臣師の差配は実に完壁だった
You will inherit the Tohsaka family magics, Rin, without a problem.
遠坂が積み上げてきた魔道は一切の遺漏なく
凛 君に受け継がれるだろう
Isn't it about time to take your mother with us?
そろそろ お母上を連れてきてはどうかね
Yes, I'll do that.
ええ そうする
Come on, Mother.
さあ お母さん
Let's say our last goodbye to Father.
お父様に最後のお別れを言おうね
Ah, Rin?
ええと 凛
今日は誰かのお葬式なの
Is it someone's funeral today?
Yes.
そうよ お父様が死んだのよ
Father passed away.
Oh, my...
まあ大変
早く時臣さんの喪服を出さなくちゃ
I need to hurry and take out Tokiomi-san's black suit.
ねえ凛 桜の着替えを手伝ってあげて
Oh right, Rin.
Help Sakura get changed.
Oh, what should I do?
ああ どうしましょう
私も支度しなくちゃいけないのに
I have to get ready too.
My dear, your necktie's crooked.
ほら あなた ネクタイが曲がっていますよ
しっかりしてください
You need to look good.
After all, you're the proud father of Rin and Sakura.
あなたは凛と桜の自慢のお父様なんですよ
I'll be leaving Japan again for a while.
またしばらく 私は日本を留守にするが
今後について 何か不安はあるかね
Do you have any concerns about the future?
No!
ないわよ あんたに頼ることなんて 何も
There's nothing I'll need your help for.
We will meet again in six months.
次に会うのは半年後だ
I will perform the second Crest transplantation then.
その時に二度目の刻印移植も執り行う
Make sure you monitor your physical condition very closely.
体調管理には充分に気をつけるように
I'd do that even if you didn't tell me!
言われなくても解ってるわ
Rin.
凛 これよりお前は名実共に遠坂の当主となる
From now on, you are officially the Tohsaka family head.
To commemorate this day, I'd like to give you a present.
今日この日のために 私から門出の品を贈りたい
An Azoth dagger.
アゾット剣
When my master acknowledged
the results of my training, he gave it to me.
かつて私が魔術の修行の成果を我が師に認められた折
戴いた品だ
You can have it.
以後 これはお前が持つといい
This was Father's...
これが お父様の
I'm here again...
また ここに
Everyone...
みんな
ランス ロット
Lancelot...
I could not stop myself from loving Guinevere, so I was never able to forgive myself.
私はギネヴィアへの想いを捨てられない
私自身が許せなかった
However, King Arthur...
だがアーサー王
You never questioned me for my crimes.
貴方は私の罪を問うことも
You never sought recompense.
償いを求めることもせず
You simply continued to stand before us in your righteousness.
ただ私たちの前で正しく在り続けた
But I desired judgment at your hands.
しかし 私は貴方の手で裁かれたかった
Had your anger judged me, I might not have fallen
onto the path of madness in my search for atonement.
貴方自身の怒りによって裁かれていたならば
私は償いを求めて 狂気の道に堕ちずに済んだかもしれない
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい
私が 私なんかが
I...
I am not worthy...
But I can say this much with certainty, King Arthur.
ただこれだけは言える
アーサー王
Someday, I will win the Holy Grail.
いつの日か 必ず聖杯を
You were the greatest among all kings.
貴方こそが最高の王であった
All who served you...
貴方の元に仕えた誰もが
I shouldn't have...
王になるべきは
...felt the same way.
そう 思っていました
...become king.
私では なかった
After that, I visited the Einzberns many times.
あの後僕は 何度もアインツベルンを訪れたが
But as I had not returned with the Grail,
Jubstacheit never opened up the forest's magic field.
聖杯を持ち帰らなかった僕に
ユーブスタクハイトは森の結界を開くことはぜず
もう二度とイリヤに会うことは叶わなかった
I never saw Ilya again.
However...
だが
Ilya was the last person I would lose.
イリヤを最後に僕の人生から奪われた人間は一人もいない
My life was meant to be full of loss.
失うばかりだったはずの人生なのに
But everyone is still here, just like when we first met.
皆 出会った日から変わらずともにいる
I adopted the boy, Shirou, that I saved that day.
僕は あの日助けた少年 士郎を養子として引き取った
— Five Years Later —
おい
Hey.
Hey, old man.
おい 爺さん
If you're gonna sleep, do it in your bed.
寝るならちゃんと布団に行けよ 爺さん
Right...
いや 大丈夫だよ
Nah, I'm fine.
When I was little, I wanted to be a champion of justice.
子供の頃 僕は正義の味方に憧れてた
なんだよそれ 憧れてたって 諦めたのかよ
What?
You wanted to be one?
Did you give up?
うん 残念ながらね
Yeah.
It's unfortunate, but...
ヒーローは期間限定で 大人になると名乗るのが難しくなるんだ
Being a hero is a limited-time thing.
When you grow up, it gets hard to call yourself one.
I should have realized that earlier.
そんなこと
もっと早くに気付けばよかった
I see.
そっか それじゃしょうがないな
That's just too bad, then.
Indeed.
そうだね 本当にしょうがない
You're absolutely right.
ああ 本当に いい月だ
The moon's really nice tonight.
Yeah.
うん しょうがないから 俺が代わりになってやるよ
Since you couldn't do it, I'll do it for you.
You're an adult now, so you can't do it.
爺さんは大人だからもう無理だけど
But I can.
俺なら大丈夫だろ
Leave it to me...
任せろって
Your dream.
爺さんの夢は
Right.
そうか
Yeah.
I can be at peace now.
安心した
Hey, Kerry.
ケリィはさ どんな大人になりたいの
What do you want to be when you grow up?
Well...
僕はね
I want to be a champion of justice.
正義の味方になりたいんだ
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
Kimi wo erande
君を選んで
If I could choose you
Tatta futari no yorokobi wo sagaseta nara
たった二人の 歓びを探せたなら
And search for happiness meant for just the two of us
Donna tsumetai honoo ni mi wo yakaretemo
どんな冷たい焔に身を焼かれても
Even if cold flames should sear my body
Hohoemi no chikaku
微笑みの近く
I will still be close to a smile
Kono sekai wo sunda mizu no naka e kaeshitai
この世界を 澄んだ水の中へ還したい
I want to return this world to the clear water
Kanashimi dake kese wa shinai
哀しみだけ消せはしない
Sadness alone will not disappear
Sonna hito no kokoro no
そんな人の心の
With my very own hands
Kotowari sae kono te de kirisaite
理さえこの手で切り裂いて
I will tear apart even the rules governing the hearts of the suffering
down to zero we go
Kirei na tsuki no hikari wa
綺麗な月の光は
The beautiful moonlight
Tada shizuka ni hajimari e kuchite yuku yo
ただ静かに 始まりへ朽ちて行くよ
Simply and quietly shines towards the beginning and rots away
Tozasareta akogare wa mada tooku e
閉ざされた憧れは まだ遠くへ
The longing that has been sealed is still far away
Yami no naka kimi to ikita hibi no subete
闇の中 君と生きた 日々の全て
Everything about the days where we lived together in the darkness
Yasashii uta
優しい歌
A gentle song